# SAHASH SAINJU

WEB SOFTWARE ENGINEER

### INFO

PHONE (925) 394 6737

EMAIL sahash182@gmail.com

### LINKS

<u>LinkedIn</u>

Github Link

Personal website

SKILLS

HTML5, CSS3, javaScript, AJAX, Rest API, JSON

Bootstrap 4, AngularJS, jQuery, React

Google Analytics, Google Developer Tools

Word Press, Wix, Weebly, Joomla,

Ruby on Rails, Node, C++, Mean, Spfx, Git

MongoDB, Active Record, MySQL, PostgreSQL

Agile Methodologies, TDD, BDD

Mocha, Chai, Rspec

Sublime Text, Github, Heroku, Bitbucket, Atom, Jira, Asana, VS Code

### LANGUAGES

English

. . . . .

Nepalese

Hindi ● ● ● ●

#### PROFILE

Seeking new exciting opportunity to learn new technologies and come up with innovative problem solving techniques to build futuristic apps.

Full Stack Web Software Engineer with 8+ years of experience in Web Development. Completed Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science with an addition of a Web Development Immersive Course from General Assembly in San Francisco, CA.

#### EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

### Web Software Engineer II, Robert Half International Nov 2016 - Present

San Ramon, CA

Building web based applications for company's various different needs and provide continued support to the business partners on intranet Applications. Used Reactjs SPFx to migrate Classic to Modern Webparts. Design and build React components to integrate into Sharepoint Modern Webparts for internal web applications.

Technologies: SPFx, React, Typescript, javascript, CSS3, HTML5, jQuery, Photoshop, Sublime Text, Snagit,

## Web Developer, Cibo Studios Mar 2016 – Nov 2016

San Francisco, CA

UX/UI development, gathering requirements from client and managed software improvements. Agile work environment with tracking and finding detailed issues of the web pages and fixing it before delivering to client. Responsible for responsive designs and fulfilling the requirement of clients to meet their business goals.

Technologies: HTML5, CSS3, Mocha, Jira, javascript, CSS, jQuery, Asana, NodeJS

## Web Developer / Web Design, Lumigrow Oct 2015 - Mar 2016

Novato, CA

Followed agile methodology to break down tasks and testing software as well as hardware components for new product release. Pair Programming and wrote functional, unit and integrated testing.

Technologies: HTML5, CSS3, javascript, Jira, jQuery, Mocha

# Web Developer / Web Design / UX Design, The White Zone Org [Non-Profit] [Part Time Position]

El Cerrito, CA

Apr 2015 - Apr 2016

Ensured the technical feasibility of the UI/UX designs. Managing events and collaborating with team members across the globe for data visualization. Designed banners, logos and flyers for social and cultural events.

Technologies: HTML5, CSS3, javascript, jQuery, Photoshop, Sketch

# Front End Developer, Humana Contractor Mar 2013 – Apr 2015

Louisville, KY

Engaged in training with the teams clarifying business stories and ensuring business delivery and production turn. Participated in pair programming and TDD. Built iterated prototypes rapidly using customer feedback.

Technologies: HTML5, CSS3, javascript, jQuery, Mocha, UI, MVC, Ruby on Rails

# Web Developer, Mountain State University (Intern) Aug 2011 – Dec 2012

Beckley, WV

Designed and developed various college web pages and layouts. Pair Programming with senior team members developing the webpages.

Technologies: Dream Weaver, javascript, HTML, CSS, Photoshop

### EDUCATION

# Mountain State University, Associate's Degree in Computer Science

Beckley, WV

Jan 2009 - May 2011

# Grantham University, Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science

Lenexa, KS

Jan 2012 - May 2015

# General Assembly, Web Development Immersive Course

San Francisco, CA

May 2016 - Aug 2016

### REFERENCES

Abiy Demilew from Robert Half International abiy.demilew@roberthalf.com

Roja Sorokorensky from Robert Half International roja.sorokorensky@roberthalf.com